<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Tommy Cao</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Tommy Cao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CS50x - Week 3 Review</title>
      <link>/blog/cs50-week0-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cs50-week0-copy/</guid>
      <description>CS50 Week 3 Status: In progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS50x - Week 2 Review</title>
      <link>/blog/cs50-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cs50-week2/</guid>
      <description>CS50 Week 2 Status: Done.
Lecture: This week, the lecture explored how code is compiled by process of how compilers preprocess, compile, assemble and link the code to create executable programs.
Other things I learned include:
An introduction to visualising memory, variables and arrays. Rubber duck debugging. Array initialisation/referencing and parallels with char data type. The arguments argc + argv and how they can be used within programs, contrasting those with so far that had argument void.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS50x - Week 1 Review</title>
      <link>/blog/cs50-week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cs50-week1/</guid>
      <description>CS50 Week 1 Status: Done
Lecture: The week’s lecture touched on the concept of good practices, as well as expanding on logic introduced with the code-blocks, with their respective C language implementations.
I had knowledge of concepts such as data types, variables and use of the CLI but chose to not skip through any of the content — part of the reason I wanted to do an introductory course was so I could clear any misunderstandings I might hold, in generally start with a fresh perspective anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS50x - Week 0 Review</title>
      <link>/blog/cs50-week0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cs50-week0/</guid>
      <description>As I am still taking my first formative steps in my IT career, I find myself constantly curious on everything there is out there to learn. Consistently, there seems to be a single skill that is universally valued for it&amp;rsquo;s meaningful utility — programming.
I found the CS50x course while looking for a course that would provide an effective foundation, and since there seems to be a universal agreement on the quality of this course, I figured it perfectly suitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post!</title>
      <link>/blog/15062022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/15062022/</guid>
      <description>Not super sure what I have planned for this website &amp;ndash; but I figure it&amp;rsquo;s better to do, experiment, and start defining things later when I develop better experience and opinions.
For now, it&amp;rsquo;s a learning blog and portfolio website!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
